Edmund L. Nichols papers, Inclusive: circa 1913-2010, Bulk: 1941-2009
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials
- Diplomatic Service, 1967-2010, undated; 3
  - Madrid, Spain, 1982-2010, undated; 4
    - U.S. Agricultural Counselor Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Achievements and Performance Appraisals, 1987-1993 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Calle Velazquez Newspapers, 1993 March-June (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - U.S. Agricultural Counselor, 1986-1992 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Foreign Agriculture Articles, 1985-1993 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - U.S. Agricultural Counselor Appointment, 1985-1989, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Invitations, 1987-1993, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Juan Carlos I y Sofia Reyes de Espana silver medallion keychain, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 12)
    - Congreso de los Diputados, Madrid, bronze medallion in leather pouch, 1985 (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 13)
    - Meritorious Honor Award, Department of State, Sandra Nichols, framed, 1989 October (Box 19 OVZ, Folder 1)
    - Canary Islands Agricultural Appreciation wooden and silver plaque, 1989 September 12 (Box 20 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Brussels, Belgium, 1989-1993; 5
    Subseries V. Brussels, Belgium, spans Nichols’ second-to-last overseas role from 1989-1992, as U.S. Agricultural Minister-Counselor, U.S. Mission to the European Communities. This subseries contains speeches, invitations and guest lists for parties and events, public correspondence and official business documents, travel mementos, and personal correspondence and photographs. Subseries V. contains some French language material.
    - Resumé, circa 1989 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Conference Speeches, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Personal Correspondence and Mementos, 1990-1993 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Appointment to Agricultural Minister-Counselor to the European Community, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Position Evaluations, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Agricultural Counselor Correspondence (1 of 2), 1989-1992 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - U.S. Agricultural Counselor Correspondence (2 of 2), 1989-1992 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - U.S. Agricultural Counselor Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Guest Lists and Invitations, 1989-1992 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Invitations, 1990-1992 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - U.S. Agricultural Counselor Correspondence and Work, 1989-1992 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Agricultural Conferences and Programs, 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Personal, circa 1913-2009, undated; 4
  This series contains material relating to the life and family of Ed Nichols. It is arranged in two subseries: General and Correspondence. Subseries I. General, holds personal items that are not correspondence, namely photographs, materials relating to life events, high school and college education, reunions, family history, music and drama, speeches and essays, and other memorabilia. Subseries II. Correspondence, contains letters to and from the Nichols family, relatives, and friends. The majority of this correspondence is from Nichols’ diplomatic service abroad and may contain duplicated material from Series III.
  - General, circa 1913-2009, undated; 1
    - Photographs and Life Events, circa 1950-2004 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Birth Certificate Copy, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Democratic National Convention, 1977-1980 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Texas Inauguration, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Texas State Democratic Convention, 1974 September 17 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Biographical, 2004-2009 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Hardin-Simmons University, Bachelor of Music, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Hardin-Simmons University Photographs, circa 1953-2004 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Agricultural Policy and Economics Speeches, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Music Recitals, 1953-1997 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Selective Service Identification Cards and Austin Federation of Musicians Card, 1949-1967 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Grade School Certificates, 1943-2004 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - French Language Certificate, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Nichols Family History, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Nichols’ Writings for the Throckmorton Tribune, 1997-2004 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Family Photographs, circa 1913-2005 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Pet Documents, 1967-1986 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Retirement, 1994-2009 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Throckmorton High Mementos, 1947-1949 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Throckmorton High Mementos, 1941-2004 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Throckmorton High Mementos, 1979-2008 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Throckmorton High 50th Anniversary Reunion, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Throckmorton High 60th Anniversary Reunion, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Throckmorton High 60th Anniversary Reunion Show and Tell, 1948-2009 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Throckmorton High 61st Anniversary Reunion, 2000 June (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Throckmorton High, Everybody’s Crazy Script, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Degree Transcripts, 1947-1962 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Hardin-Simmons University Mementos (1 of 4), 1950-2004, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Hardin-Simmons University Mementos (2 of 4), 1950-2004, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Hardin-Simmons University Mementos (3 of 4), 1950-2004, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Hardin-Simmons University Mementos (4 of 4), 1950-2004, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Hardin-Simmons University 50th Anniversary Reunion, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Hardin-Simmons University 50th Anniversary Reunion, 2002-2003 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Alpha Chi, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - “Hymn Playing” Music Workbook, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Stamps Quartet Gospel Music Book: Gospel Bells, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Stamps-Baxter Gospel Music Book: Golden Key, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Stamps-Baxter Gospel Music Book: Gospel Tide, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Stamps-Baxter Gospel Music Book: Starlit Crown, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Glad Tidings Gospel and Church Hymns Music Book, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - John C. White, Commissioner of Agriculture, 1972-1980, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - The Face of Rural America, Yearbook of Agriculture, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Throckmorton High, School Textbooks (1 of 3), 1942-1945 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Throckmorton High, School Textbooks (2 of 3), 1942-1945 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Throckmorton High, School Textbooks (3 of 3), 1942-1945 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Faye Nichols, State of Texas Certificate of Appreciation, 1983 April 21 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Nichols Family Christmas Cards, 1965-1984 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Political Photographs and Memorabilia, 1963-1993 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Inaugural Committee, 1973-1977 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Speeches, Essays, and Sermons, 1973-2009 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Nichols Family in Austin, 1964-1973 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Toastmasters International Speeches, circa 1970-1977 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Profession-Related Speeches, 2004-2009, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - The President’s House, Washington: framed painting signed by Jimmy and Rosalynn Carter, circa 1977 (Box OVZ, Folder 1)
    - LOOK Magazine, 1969 July 15 (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 6)
    - Painting by Bernhard, 1959 (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 7)
    - White House Winter Painting, undated (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 8)
    - Lyndon B. Johnson, School of Public Affairs, Twentieth Anniversary, thin gold-plated ornament, 1970-1971 (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 14)
    - Jimmy Carter Presidential Seal tie bar, gold-plated, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 15)
    - U.S. Marine Corps 209th Anniversary, red plastic coaster, 1984 (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 16)
    - Hardin-Simmons University 50th University wood plaque, 2003 April (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 17)
    - Agricultural Trade Office digital thermometer, silver in white box, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 18)
    - Jimmy Carter Presidential Seal pin, blue and gold-plated, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 19)
    - National Council of Farmer Cooperatives leather keychain, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 20)
    - Distinguished Alumni 2004, Class of ’49 laminated poster (Box 19 OVZ, Folder 2)
    - Hardin-Simmons University Distinguished Alumni Award, purple and gold wooden plaque, 2000 October 20 (Box 19 OVZ, Folder 3)
    - Throckmorton High School Distinguished Alumnus Award, wooden plaque, 2004 October 23 (Box 19 OVZ, Folder 4)
    - Nameplate wooden block, undated (Box 19 OVZ, Folder 5)
    - Toastmasters International, Club Past President Outstanding Service Award, wooden plaque, 1972 (Box 20 OVZ, Folder 8)
    - Throckmorton High School Diploma, 1949 May 24 (Box 20 OVZ, Folder 9)
    - The University of Texas Master of Music Diploma, 1958 May 31 (Box 20 OVZ, Folder 10)
    - Jack Daniel Distillery Souvenir Deed, 1983 (Box 20 OVZ, Folder 11)
    - European Union: 20th Century and Beyond Lecture Poster, 1995 February 28 (Box 20 OVZ, Folder 12)
    - The Face of Rural America photographs, undated (Box 20 OVZ, Folder 13)
    - The Face of Rural America negatives, undated (Box 20 OVZ, Folder 14)
    - TIME Magazine “Man on the Moon”, 1969 July 25 (Box 21 OVZ, Folder 1)
    - The Texas Observer “J. Frank Dobie of Texas”, 1964 July 24 (Box 21 OVZ, Folder 2)
    - Throckmorton Tribune “The Hometown” Part One, 2004 October 15 (Box 21 OVZ, Folder 3)
    - Throckmorton Tribune “The Hometown” Part Two, 2004 October 22 (Box 21 OVZ, Folder 4)
    - The Austin American “Kennedy in Peacemaker Role”, 1963 November 22 (Box 21 OVZ, Folder 5)
    - Austin American-Statesman “Young Suspect is Captured in Kennedy’s Assassination”, 1963 November 23 (Box 21 OVZ, Folder 6)
    - Austin American-Statesman “A President Resigns”, 1974 August 10 (Box 21 OVZ, Folder 7)
    - Austin American-Statesman “Nixon Resigns”, 1974 August 9 (Box 21 OVZ, Folder 8)
    - Dallas Morning News “Kennedy Slain on Dallas Street”, 1963 November 23 (Box 21 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1993; 2
    - Hawaii, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Family, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Family, 1988-1991 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Family, 1988-1990 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Friends, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Brussels, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Texas Governor, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Friends, 1987-1991, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Copenhagen (1 of 2), 1982-1988 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Copenhagen (2 of 2), 1982-1988 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Vice President Walter Mondale, 1976-1978 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Texas State Government, 1972-1977 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Family, 1988-1991 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Family, 1987-1990 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Family, 1985-1990 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Madrid (1 of 3), 1986-1993 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Madrid (2 of 3), 1986-1993 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Madrid (3 of 3), 1986-1993 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Family, 1987-1992 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Family, 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), 1984, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Family, 1988-1991 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Appointments, 1979-1982 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Friends, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Rome (1 of 2), 1979-1981 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Rome (2 of 2), 1979-1981 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Rome-Madrid, 1985-1990 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Friends, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Friends, Sarah Weddington, 1988-1991 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Friends (1 of 3), 1987-1991 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Friends (2 of 3), 1987-1991 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Friends (3 of 3), 1987-1991 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Overseas, General, 1979-1993 (Box 14, Folder 17)